Welcome to the next level.
Sonic the Hedgehog 2 is a action, adventure,
family film directed by Jeff Fowler.
After settling in Green Hills, Sonic is eager to prove
he has what it takes to be a true hero.
His test comes when Dr.
Robotnik returns, this time with a new partner, Knuckles, in search for
an emerald that has the power to destroy civilizations.
Sonic teams up with his own sidekick, Tails, and together they embark on a
globe-trotting journey to find the emerald before it falls into the wrong hands.
Sonic (voice), played by Ben Schwartz.
Tom Wachowski, played by James Marsden.
Maddie Wachowski, played by Tika Sumpter.
Tails (voice), played by Colleen O'Shaughnessey.
Knuckles (voice), played by Idris Elba.
Dr. Robotnik, played by Jim Carrey.
Sonic the Hedgehog 2 is a 2022 action-adventure comedy
film based on the Sonic video game series.
The second in the Sonic the Hedgehog film series, it was directed by Jeff
Fowler and written by Pat Casey, Josh Miller, and John Whittington.
Jim Carrey, Ben Schwartz, James Marsden, Tika Sumpter, Natasha Rothwell, Colleen O'Shaughnessey and
Adam Pally reprise their roles, with Shemar Moore and Idris Elba joining the cast.
In the film, Sonic and his friend Tails embark on a journey to
find the Master Emerald before their nemesis, Dr.
Ivo Robotnik, and his accomplice, Knuckles the Echidna.
Following the success of the first film in 2020, Paramount Pictures announced the
sequel in May 2020, with Fowler, Casey, Miller and the cast returning.
Filming took place from March to June 2021 in Vancouver and Hawaii.
The film was loosely inspired by the video games Sonic the Hedgehog 2
(1992), Sonic the Hedgehog 3 (1994), and Sonic & Knuckles (1994).
Sonic the Hedgehog 2 was theatrically released in several markets on March 30,
2022, in the United States on April 8, and in Japan on August 19.
Like its predecessor, it set several box office records for a video game film and received mixed reviews from
critics, who praised the performances and action sequences but criticized the screenplay and runtime.
It grossed $405.4 million worldwide.
A television series, Knuckles, and a third film were released in 2024.
The film explores themes of mad scientist, sequel, revenge,
based on video game, duringcreditsstinger.
The tone is lighthearted.